# TAI ZHANG

Creative problem solver with deep experience in user experience design, product management, and web technologies. Detail-oriented, hands-on maker with a passion for creating useful and usable products. Seasoned leader with a knack for focusing on what's important, providing targeted direction, and delivering high-quality results.

# **EXPERIENCE** JustFab | Los Angeles, CA

Fashion e-commerce startup valued at \$1 billion in our most recent round of funding. I have been a leader on the technology teams for both the consumer-facing sites (mobile & web) and back-end enterprise systems.

# **Director of User Experience - Fast Fashion**

2015 - NOW

- Identify opportunities and lead the design of solutions to improve usability, increase conversion, and grow various business areas.
- Resolved friction points in the registration and login processes, resulting in a 20% lift in new orders and a 15% increase in repeat revenue.
- Researched, pitched, and executed a series of optimizations on the mobile site for checkout, product pages, navigation, and registration.
- Championed the redesign of our internal AB testing platform to support multiple, independently
  concurrent tests, dramatically increasing testing velocity and data accuracy.
- Directed the UX and UI design for the front-end experience and internal tools supporting the new personal styling business, PS by JustFab (launching December 2015).

#### **Director of Product - Fast Fashion**

2014 - 2015

- Led an agile product development team responsible for supporting both long-term technology projects and daily operations for the JustFab and ShoeDazzle business units.
- Launched the redesign of the JustFab mobile and desktop site experiences to support a business expansion from shoes and accessories into apparel and head-to-toe looks.
- Designed and delivered the customer-facing experience of the new loyalty rewards program.

## **Technical Product Manager - Enterprise Systems**

2014

- Collaborated with business stakeholders, users, designers, and engineers across multiple teams to define product vision and strategy for internal software projects supporting all JustFab, Inc. brands.
- Owned the design and development of an iOS inventory management system that facilitates the storage and photography of over 10,000 active product samples.
- Researched and established business rules and requirements to develop a fraud mitigation system that reduces credit card chargebacks and lost revenue of over \$1MM per year.

## McMaster-Carr Supply Company | Santa Fe Springs, CA & Elmhurst, IL

Part of a highly selective rotational management program with a strong focus on developing generalist managers at one of the leading suppliers in the \$100+ billion/year Maintenance, Repair, and Operations (MRO) industry. I spent several years working in the technology teams where I managed both product teams for both web and sales.

#### **Product Manager - Customer Correspondence**

2011 - 2012

- Improved customer communication and simplified their internal workflows by redesigning McMaster-Carr's system-generated documents for order confirmations and quotations.
- Led the development of a new document generation system to be used for all automated documents, saving \$1MM between labor and postage costs.
- \* Advised executives and project teams across the department on information design strategies.

#### Product Manager - McMaster.com

2006 - 2007

- Conducted competitive research, formulated technical and business requirements, developed interaction flows, and redesigned the user interface to improve how customers interact with their order history information online.
- Improved the user experience throughout the company's e-commerce site by leading a team of engineers to develop a responsive and dynamic new web application framework.
- Worked with customers in the field to understand use cases and conduct A/B interface testing.

**EXPERIENCE** 

Web Developer

2005 - 2006

Continued

• Designed UI changes, implemented technical solutions, and analyzed behavioral metrics to improve various ordering, security, and account management features of McMaster.com.

### **McMaster-Carr - Additional Experience**

While at McMaster-Carr I had an opportunity to run several operational departments in publishing, warehouse operations, and finance, which helped expand my leadership skills and holistic business understanding.

# Finance Manager - Accounts Receivable and Credit Risk

2012 - 2014

 Led the West Coast region's accounts receivable department of 2 junior managers and 23 account specialists to establish strategies that reduce aging debt, achieving a reduction of 25% in financial losses between 2012 and 2013 by improving targeted reviews of risky customers.

#### Warehouse & Logistics Manager - Parcel Packing

2012

• Oversaw a department of 15 employees to assemble and pack over 10,000 daily shipments.

**Art Director** 2007 - 2011

- Managed a creative department of 20 print & web content creators, photographers, and retouchers.
- Provided information design direction and strategy for Product Line Managers to create presentations that clearly illustrate the features and benefits of complex industrial products.
- Oversaw the digital and physical production of the company's 3,800 page catalog and graphic assets, ensuring high-quality work while adhering to weekly production deadlines.

# **EDUCATION**

# Cornell University, College of Arts & Sciences | Ithaca, NY

2001 - 2005

BA, Information Science, concentration in Human-Centered Systems (HCI)

SKILLS	Design	Product/Analytics	Technical	Other
	UX/UI Design	Agile/Scrum	HTML 5	Photography
	Information Architecture	Kanban	CSS/SASS	Chinese (Mandarin)
	Adobe Creative Suite	JIRA	JavaScript/jQuery	
	Axure/Balsamiq	Google Analytics	SQL	
	Print Design & Publishing	Tableau	Git	
	Art Direction	Good Old Excel		